In this module will be taking a closer look at
the material settings,
which involves adding new fabrics and changing their physical properties
as well as their outer traits.
Now we will start off with changing just the colours,
maybe adding some patterns and so on,
and I will demonstrate all of this to the upper
part of our outfit.
So these two patterns and the sleeves.
Now if we take a look at the optic browser
to the fabric tab,
we see that we only have one default fabric that
is applied to all of our patterns,
so will start off by adding a new one by
clicking here.
And renaming it to top.
Now we're going to drag and drop this newly made
fabric to the patterns.
So the two front ones.
As well as the back ones.
We're going to leave these strips of fabric out.
And this leaves. We're also going to check by clicking
on the top.
If the fabric was applied.
As you can see, it gets an orange outline and
we see that we've applied it successfully.
Now let's take a look at the settings that we
have,
which opened up in the property editor.
First thing you'll notice is that you can make different
textures for the front,
back or side of the fabric an each tab has
the same settings,
so you can really customize this as much as you
like,
but will stick to changing the front side for now
though.
So of course, the obvious thing that we can change
is of course the color,
and if I click on it,
you see that I'm able to choose from every kind
of color I want.
I can even use the eyedropper tool if I need
too,
and so on. So let's go for a very dark
black color for now and hit OK.
Underneath the color option we have the specular color,
which gives us a shining's effect and if I demonstrate
this,
if I click on it and let's go for something
like wider,
you can see that I get this effect that looks
almost like leather so I can achieve very interesting effects
with this.
And I can also adjust the shininess factor so I
can make it very subtle,
or I can make it very pronounced.
Depending on what kind of effect I want now,
I can even upload a specular map to this and
I'm just going to quickly upload a texture that I
have by clicking on this icon.
And I'm going to choose this ornament image that I
have right here.
An if I zoom in.
You can see the subtle ornament within our shirt,
and it's usually more pronounced when the light is hitting
the fabric and hides when the fabric goes into the
shadows.
Course I can also manipulate this as well with the
shininess factor to make it more or less visible.
If I would like to.
Next, we have the emission colour.
The emission color is for clothing that basically emits light,
so I can easily change it right here,
but we don't need that for now,
so let's just cancel this and I'm also going to
delete the specular map by pressing on this icon right
here.
There's one thing that we forgot,
and at the very top of the list,
and that is a texture,
so we can also add our own textures.
Maybe some that we find online,
or some that we've created ourselves.
So I simply just click on this icon as with
the specular map.
And again, I'm going to use this ornament image again,
so just going to open that up.
And once I applied this texture,
I can also put a color on top of it.
So if I choose white I get the original image.
But I can also apply my own colors and you
see I get very different effects.
So this is very neat.
You can really customize your textures and patterns this way,
so I'm just gonna leave it to a bit of
an orange and hit OK.
Now the next thing that I would like to show
you is how to further manipulate these patterns,
because as you can see the pattern is so small
that it's beginning to repeat itself and maybe I would
like to resize it rotated or maybe changes its position
an I can easily do that with the help of
the edit texture tool that can be found in the
2D window right here or even in the 3D window
right here so I can edit and move the texture
in the 3D or in the 2D window.
It doesn't even matter. So if I zoom in.
If I click on the pattern you see that I
get this handle right here and I'm able to move
the patterns.
In any way that I would like.
In the upper right corner I'm also able to rotate
the patterns.
An I can also resize them.
Or maybe just the Y or the X axis.
You can also apply these changes under texture transformation.
That can be found under the property editor.
So right below the emission color we have the texture
transformation.
So if you would like to move rotate or.
Anything else by an exact number,
you can just input that here so you don't need
to do here manually.
And then the next option that we have is the
Opacity.
If I lower it, I get a see through material.
So we took a look.
This is basically all of the settings that involve sort
of the outer appearance of our texture.
And the next important tap that we have is the
physical property which involves the property of the fabric that
we have an we're going to tackle this further in
the next clip.